# STEVEN STRINGER

ANALYTICS PROFESSIONAL

## CONTACT

(682) 305-5177 STRINGER.STEVENJ@OUTLOOK.COM DALLAS, TX

## **PROFILE**

I'm an experienced analytics professional who has had the opportunity to implement my knowledge of analytics in the areas of airline operations, auto lending, and the consumer financial service industry.

Through my graduate studies in Business Analytics and my career experience I've developed skills in machine learning model development, deployment, and presentation for business guidance and strategy.

## SKILLS

- SQL
- ETL and Data Management
- Google Cloud Platform
- Tableau
- Python
- R
- SAS
- Statistical Modeling
- Time Series Forecasting
- Machine Learning
- Alteryx

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR CREDIT RISK ANALYST

REGIONAL MANAGMENT CORP | JAN 2020 - PRESENT

- Develop and implement bankruptcy scoring model together with IT to guide business rules, provide model testing, and validation of results as needed. Conduct trend analysis on model results to support state level criteria with a focus on loan volume- credit loss trade off
- Analyze trends and performance of custom credit scorecards to ensure that cutoffs align with target delinquency, loss rates, and appropriate volume targets. Use results to advise on the implementation of new business strategies, score cutoff changes and credit policy.
- Support of direct mail marketing initiatives, including credit risk review and approval of prescreening criteria changes, new models to support campaigns, and tracking of program results.
- Provide analysis of portfolio performance to recommend any necessary credit policy changes to help the company achieve delinquency and net credit loss goals within 5-10% of the set budget.

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST - MARKETING ANALYTICS**

GM FINANCIAL | MAR 2019 - JAN 2020

- Developed a decision tree model to determine customers to target for rewards program marketing campaigns with SAS Model Studio and provided the recommendations to leaders based on the model's results.
- Delivered analysis, insights, and recommendations to support enhancements of email marketing campaigns, direct marketing campaigns, and user behavior reports on self-service portals.
- Measured performance of online and offline campaigns through reporting on marketing KPIs.
- Rewrote code and rebuilt programs to improve the performance of legacy reports.
- Worked with various internal owners and third parties to research, understand, and educate our team around trends in data and marketing mediums we needed to explore.

#### **REPORTING ANALYST**

SOUTHWEST ARILINES | SEP 2018 - MAR 2019

- Prepared and cleansed millions of rows of data from CRM systems, call center records, and social media sources.
- Processed high-volume and complex data to create dashboards and automate reports with Tableau and Alteryx for daily, weekly, and monthly reports.
- Developed demand forecasts, volume forecasts, and other statistical models to recommend operational plans to senior leaders.
- Managed and fulfilled ad hoc interdepartmental requests by meeting
  with stakeholders to identify their needs, pulling data from appropriate
  sources, validating the data, and providing models for analysis and
  presentation.

# **EDUCATION**

MASTER OF SCIENCE, BUSINESS ANALYTICS

UNIVERSITY OF DALLAS | 2018 - 2019

MASTER OF ARTS, CLASSICS

UNIVERSITY OF DALLAS | 2014 - 2017

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, RELIGION

LIBERTY UNIVERSITY | 2010 - 2014